# Mahendra AR

#### Full Stack Developer

Focused motivator seeking an opportunity to learn constantly and upgrade my knowledge and skills. I want to secure a challenging position that allows me to get perfection in the field of IT. So I want to work with a progressive organisation where I could utilise my knowledge and skills for mutual growth of company and me.

- Highly skilled software development professional having around 2+ years of developing experience.
- Strong understanding of JavaScript (ES6+), Object Oriented Programming (OOPS), Functional Programming concept and it's quirks.
- Excellent understanding of handling synchronous & asynchronous execution.
- Extensive experience in developing Non-Blocking I/O Applications and RestFull API's using NodeJS, ExpressJS frameworks, mongoose ORM and MongoDB database.
- Extensive experience of Angular and React for developing feature rich, high performance component based UI.
- Integration and deployment experience of applications to AWS.
- Highly adaptable in quickly changing technical environments with very strong organisational and analytical skills.
- Can work independently and also as efficient team member.



# **Personal Info**

**Phone** 

+91-8105693159

E-mail mahendra0859@gmail.com

Date of birth

1994-03-25

**WWW** https://mahendra0859.github.io/portfol

io/

https://www.linkedin.com/in/mahendr

LinkedIn

**GitHub** 

a-ar-449954150/

https://github.com/mahendra0859/



HTML5, CSS3,

Java Script,

Bootstrap, NodeJS.

ExpressJS,

React, Type Script, MongoDB,

SQL

MEAN STACK,

MERN STACK

(MongoDB,

ExpressJS, Angular, ReactJS

NodeJS)

Git, Continuous Integration (CI) &

Delivery (CD),

AWS(EC2, S3 Bucket, ), Linux,

Firebase





Continuous



# **Experience**

2018-01 -2019-03

# **MEAN Stack Developer**

## **UIPEP Technologies Private Limited**

#### **Responsibilities:**

- Work closely with internal development, product management and design
- Managing client communications and requirement gatherings for projects.
- Identifying ways to improve designs, efficiency, performance and development processof applications.
- Worked as a developer of the Node. Js development and Frontend development team.
- Deliver quality code by applying the best development practices.

2019-04 present

### **Full Stack Developer**

Arraign Technologies Pvt Ltd

#### Responsibilities:

- Provide technical leadership at a project level.
- Contribute to comprehensive documentation that supports the development.
- Deploying applications and maintaining them in productions.
- Server-based Node.Js development.
- features, MongoDB setup and query operations. Maintaining node applications using git and AWS EC2.

Provide strong technical guidance by research and analysis of Node.Js

**Education** 

2012-05 -

# The National Degree College

2015-11

- Bachelor of Computer Applications BCA, Computer Science, Bangalore University
- Aggregate 6.2 GPA

Dayananda Sagar Institutions

2016-06 -2018-06

- Master of Computer Applications MCA, Computer Science, Bangalore
- University
- Aggregate 7.9 GPA



- 1) **D8AMATIKS:** Applications for GDPR Privacy Protection Compliance Services
- Description: D8amatiks GDPR compliance solution is an automated DIY GDPR toolkit for small and medium sized business that is affordable and simple to use. It's automated DIY toolkit will empower client's to set up a GDPR compliant data protection framework and help them to manage GDPR compliance on an ongoing basis without
- having to engage costly external experts. • Plat forms : Express.JS, MongoDB, Node.JS , Angular 5
- Team size: 4
- · Key Features and Requirements :
- -> Two servers and three web applications powers complex and dynamic GDPR toolkit.
- -> Admin panel for control on users , referrals , coupons and dynamic tree based structure for manage sections, questions, recommendations, conditions and dynamic documents.
- -> Questionnaire module for collect user 's data using sections , questions and conditions execution logic based on rules configured in the admin panel.
- -> Generate dynamic gap report, recommendations and output documents based on user 's answers for implement solutions .
- Links:
- -> https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=yzznQCkb4ME
- -> https://www.d8amatiks.com/#/
- 2) **CORBATA**: Ride-Sharing App
- Description: Corbata is an app for both rider and driver for providing cab services, renting the self-driven cars and scheduling the cab services for particular time slot or for certain days.

Plat forms: Express.JS, MongoDB, Node.JS, Angular 5, Java for Android, Swift for IoS

- Team size: 10
- Key Features and Requirements : -> web application, two servers, android application, IoS application for rider and
- driver.
- -> Admin panel for control on users , promotions , coupons and invoice. -> Generate dynamic invoice for the respective ride.
- DODA Calculators: Pump Calculator • Description: Doda is an simple app used to recommend the pumps based
- on the requirement of the user • Plat forms: Express.JS, MongoDB, Node.JS, Angular 5, Java for Android,
- Swift for IoS • Team size: 3
- -> web application, android app, IoS app and a server.
- Key Features and Requirements :
- -> web, android and IoS app will take the necessary inputs from the end-user. -> Backend server based on the predefined logic and users input recommend
- certain pumps.
- Description: Cohora is a self-sustaining platform that consolidates 75% of

4) COHORA

- your business activities related to engaging and empowering your customerled communities. The platform provides continuous engagement with your user communities into meaningful conversations. • Plat forms: Express.JS, MongoDB, Node.JS, React, Type Script, Java for
- Android, Swift for IoS • Team size: 6
- 5) ELSPECTRA • Description: elSpectra is a techno-functional creative agency that helps B2B

Links: https://cohora.com/#/

6) VENDSMART

- & Tech/IT firms to sell better & faster with content services and a sales enablement platform. • Plat forms: ReactJS, Firebase • Team size: 2
- Links: https://www.elspectra.com/
- Description: elSpectra is a techno-functional creative agency that helps B2B & Tech/IT firms to sell better & faster with content services and a sales
- Plat forms : ReactJS, Firebase • Team size: 4

enablement platform.

- Links: http://vendsmart.com.au/
- 7) DIGITAL EAST
- Description: Digital East is a A.I. powered, human driven, real time bidding platform, Empowering customers to reach the desired audience and maximise return for their investment
- Plat forms : Angular 8, Angular Material, Java
- Team size: 2 Links: https://www.digitaleast.mobi/en/